Guide to the Cornell Migrant Program campus collection,1953-2006.
Cornell Migrant Program campus collection,1953-2006.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell Migrant Program campus collection, 1953-2006.
23-13-3582
Cornell Migrant Program.
48.5 cubic feet.
Audio Recordings, Correspondence, Photographs, Printed Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, reports, research studies, publicity, slides, tapes, 40 oral histories (conducted by Neil Schwartzbach of the Community and Rural Development Institute), and subject files documenting the Cornell campus migrant program and other farmworker-oriented organizations, not generally available from other sources.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Cornell Migrant Program Campus Collection adds to the existing Cornell Migrant Program Records (#23-13-3160) which documented the Wayne County, NY office of the Cornell Migrant Program. The Cornell Migrant Program was established in 1971 after a period of intense pro-farmworker advocacy by students and outside forces. Cornell had maintained a migrant labor camp in Wayne County, but bulldozed it to the ground in an attempt to quell the controversy. The Wayne County office was the center of activity for the program throughout its history, expanding gradually from a county-based effort to a state-wide one, closing in 2004 after Cornell's decision to move the farmworker program from the College of Human Ecology to the College of Agriculture and Life Sciences.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, reports, research studies, publicity, slides, tapes, 40 oral histories (conducted by Neil Schwartzbach of the Community and Rural Development Institute), and subject files documenting the Cornell campus migrant program and other farmworker-oriented organizations, not generally available from other sources.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell Migrant Program.; Castania, Kathy Fox; Dik, David W.; Embrey, Kay; Engman, Herbert J.; Hanson, Karen Tobin; John, Bruce; Johnson, Stephen P.; Mathewson, Betty Garcia; Nye, Molly; Richardson, Faith; Schwartzbach, Neil; Ward, Patricia; Community and Rural Development Institute.; Cornell Cooperative Extension.; New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences.; New York State College of Human Ecology.; Wayne County Special Migrant Project (N.Y.)
Subjects:
Migrant labor--United States.; Children of migrant laborers--Education.; Agricultural laborers--New York (State).; Labor laws and legislation--United States.
Form and Genre Terms:
Slides (photographs).; Oral histories.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
See also: >Cornell Migrant Program Records, #23-13-3160, http://resolver.library.cornell.edu/cgi-bin/EADresolver?id=RMA03160.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Early History and Program Development
Boxes: 1-3
Series II. Oral Histories
Boxes: 3, 8
Subseries IIa. Transcripts
Box: 3
Subseries IIb. Recordings
Box: 8
Series III. Programs
Boxes: 4, 5, 14-16
Series IV. Herb Engman
Boxes: 6-8
Subseries IVa. Reappointment Reviews, Annual Reports
Box: 8
Series V. Staff Correspondence and Programs
Boxes: 9-11
Series VI. Public Policy
Boxes: 11, 12
Series VII. Migrant Education
Boxes: 28-32, 52
Subseries VIIa. History, Publications
Box: 28, 52
Subseries VIIb. Migrant Education Consortium
Box: 29
Subseries VIIc. Migrant Education Census/MSRTS
Box: 32
Series VIII. Migrant Education Studies
Boxes: 17, 42
Series IX. Diversity
Boxes: 18-20
Subseries IXa. Kathy Fox Castania
Box: 20
Series X. Nutrition and Health
Boxes: 21-24
Subseries Xa. Nutrition
Box: 21
Subseries Xb. Health
Boxes: 22, 23
Subseries Xc. Health Reports
Box: 24
Series XI. Pesticides
Box: 26
Series XII. Housing
Box: 27
Series XIII. Parent Advisory Council
Box: 33
Series XIV. Migrant Museum Exhibit
Boxes: 34, 35
Series XV. Rural Opportunities
Boxes: 26-38
Series XVI. Working Together, Rural and Migrant Ministry
Box: 39
Series XVII. Articles Concerning Farmworkers and Migrant Issues
Box: 40, 49
Series XVIII. Estimates of Numbers of Farmworkers
Box: 41
Series XIX. Health Studies
Box: 42
Series XX. Farm Labor Studies and Reports, New York State
Box: 43
Series XXI. Farmworker Studies and Reports
Boxes: 44-48
Subseries XXIa. New York State
Boxes: 44, 45
Subseries XXIb. Regional
Box: 46
Subseries XXIc. U.S.
Boxes: 47, 48
Series XXII. Farmworker Related Organizations
Box: 13
Series XXIII. Videos
Box: 25, 51
Series XXIV. Posters, drawings, misc.
Box: 50
Container List
- Series I. Early History and Program Development
  - Cornell Migrant Program archives - Kay Embrey, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Creation of the agricultural workers archives - Kay Embrey, 1991-1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Permission to access Dean Palm's papers, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cornell Migrant Program logo (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - POW harvesting crop (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - POW Camp - Sodus (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Horn Farm Camp permit and building permit, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - German POW - Boller letter, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Story of Horn Farm - Herman Cohn, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Boller - Cohn correspondence, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Herman M. Cohn - eulogies, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Needs of Migrant Farm Workers - Thomas F. LaMont, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cohn Foundation establishment, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cohn Farm map, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cohn Farm report and survey, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Cohn Farm and creation of farmworker program, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Cohn Farm, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Cohn Foundation - CASH - Cornell Black Agriculturalists, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Cohn Foundation - Catherine Hertzel, 1977-1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Boyd - Call letter, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - The College of Agriculture and Agricultural Manpower, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Grower and Cornell interactions, 1969, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Cohn Farm controversy - Background, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Cornell University Senate Sense of the Body Resolution, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Union activity on Cohn Farm, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Rev. Ivory Simmons recommendation for Karen Tobin and Daniel Godfrey, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Karen Tobin appointment letter, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Wayne County Agricultural Manpower Program - David W. Dik, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Cooperative Extension Association of Wayne County - Migrant Program concerns, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Migrant Labor in Wayne County (New York State), 1971 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Migrant Report - Orange County (New York State) Cooperative Extension, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Report - Daniel D. Godfrey - June 15-Sept. 10, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Karen N. Tobin reports and correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Cohn Farm and creation of farmworker program, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Cohn Farm and creation of farmworker program, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Cohn Farm and creation of farmworker program - Stuart Mitchell, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Progress reports Wayne County (New York) Migrant Program, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Social responsibility in agriculture, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - On failing farmworkers (From Failing the People), 1972 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Continuation of Wayne County Agricultural Manpower Program, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Migrant Program offices - Wayne County, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Services for Migrant Farmworkers in Wayne County (New York State), 1973-2003 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Migrant Program - Orange County C.E. - S. Johnson, 1969-1976 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Wayne County Agricultural Manpower Program, paper by David W. Dik, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Wayne County Special Migrant Program summary, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Wayne County Special Migrant Project annual report - David Dik, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Wayne County Special Migrant Project, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Wayne County Special Migrant Project, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Cooperative Extension of Wayne County, 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Migrant Specialist - Special Migrant Project, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Cornell Inter-College Committee on Migrant Labor - S. Johnson, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Wayne County Special Migrant Project - Summary 1972-1975 - S. Johnson, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Special Migrant Program candidates, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Wayne County Special Migrant Project, 1976-01-1976-05 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Wayne County Special Migrant Project, 1976-06-1976-10 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Special Migrant Program position descriptions, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Sherry Morrison, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Transfer of Migrant Program to Rural Sociology, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Wayne County Special Migrant Project report, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Rural Economic and Social Development clippings, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Rural Economic and Social Development Program, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Rural Economic and Social Development Program, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Reports - Sherilyn Morrison, 1977-1978, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Correspondence - Bruce John (including program transfer), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Rural Economic and Social Development Migrant - New York State Cooperative Extension, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Rural Economic and Social Development general file, Migrants New York State, 1970-1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Rural Economic and Social Development Program - Statistics (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Rural Economic and Social Development - Migrant Directory, 1970-1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Migrant Program transfer to Human Ecology - Dean Jerome Ziegler, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Migrant Program continuation - Bruce John, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Cornell Migrant Program - Human Ecology, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Dean Jerome Ziegler and Cornell Migrant Program, 1979-87 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Committee of 9" - Campus/Local Advisory Committee, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Committee of Nine, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Migrant Program miscellaneous communication, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Cornell Migrant Program - Wayne County Advisory Board, 1979-1991 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Migrant Program Committee records, 1978-1981 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Cornell Migrant Program - Summary of program, 1980-1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Cornell Migrant Program reports, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Cornell Migrant Program Advisory Committee - Campus, 1981-1990 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Cornell Migrant Program reports, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Cornell Migrant Program report, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Cornell Migrant Program Review - Carol Anderson, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Cornell Migrant Program components and funding sources, 1986, 1987, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Organizational chart - Cornell Migrant Program (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Cornell Migrant Program Advisory Committee - Campus, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Proposed move of Cornell Migrant Program to CARDI, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Cornell Migrant Program Update, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Migrant Farmworker Families in New York State - "The Connection", 1995 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Cornell Migrant Program 25th Anniversary Conference (not held), 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Cornell Migrant Program report, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Deans' field trip concerning migrant labor, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Deans' meeting concerning migrant farmworkers, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Dean Firebaugh Letter to Dean Lawler concerning farmworkers, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Chair Keith Bryant's letter to Dean Darryl Lund concerning farmworkers, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Advocacy in Cornell Cooperative Extension Controversy (Kay Embrey), 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Cornell Cooperative Extension directors' migrant trip, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Engman response concerning advocacy to Deans Bannon, Henry and Cornell Cooperative Extension Director Ewert, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Cooperative Extension funding (Smith-Lever) for Cornell Migrant Program, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Complaints about Cornell Migrant Program, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Letter claiming Cornell Cooperative Extension supports terrorists, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Cornell Farmworker Advocacy Coalition (New York State), 2002 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - "Our Roots Feed Our Future" - 30th Anniversary of the Cornell Migrant Program packet, two copies, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - 30th Anniversary of the Cornell Migrant Program - Report, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - 30th Anniversary of the Cornell Migrant Program - Conference Presentations, two copies, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Cornell Migrant Program Self Study, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Cornell Migrant Program Review report, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Cornell Migrant Program review - Staff response, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Letter - Review of Cornell Migrant Program - Human Development chairs Eckenrode and Hamilton, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Dismissal letter to Herb Engman as director of Cornell Migrant Program, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Cornell Migrant Program transition team - Manual, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Cornell Migrant Program transition team - Meetings, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Agribusiness and Cornell (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Anonymous packet received concerning Chris Pawelski, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Cornell Migrant Program move to the College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Letters supporting Cornell Migrant Program in Human Ecology, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Cornell Migrant Program move to College of Agriculture and Life Scienes - Media coverage, 2004-2005 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Principles and practices concerning strategic corporate alliances, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Cornell Migrant Program - Hall of Fame, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Cornell Migrant Program staff final letter to collaborators, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Sowing Seeds for Justice Dinner - Kay Embrey, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Cornell students - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - New York Friends of Farmworkers Award - Cornell Migrant Program, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Series II. Oral Histories
  - Subseries IIa. Transcripts
    - Cornell Migrant Program Oral History - Printed documents, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Marcia Boyd interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Stuart Mitchell interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Carl Kukkonen interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Robert Gottlieb interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Jeffrey Liddle interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - W. Keith Kennedy interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Dale Corson interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Cathy Cohn Hertzel interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Karen Noble Hanson interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - David Dik interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Stephen Philip Johnson interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - George Arney interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - David Call interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Lucinda Noble interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Alice Sprout interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Abner McKee interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Donald Naeye interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Jerome Ziegler interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Bruce John interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Sid Cleveland interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Cliff DeMay interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Alison DeMarree interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Maureen Torrey interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Laura Pedersen interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Julie Suarez interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Joaquin Bermudez interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - John Lincoln interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Rick Zimmerman interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Earl Welker interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Velma Smith interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Nancy Croce interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Gerry Verbridge interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Tom Maloney interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Francille Firebaugh interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Jim Schmidt interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Molly Nye interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Kay Embrey interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Betty Garcia Mathewson interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Kathy Castania interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Gary Fitch interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - George Lamont interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Chris Pawelski interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Herb Engman interview, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Subseries IIb. Recordings
    - Lee Beebe, Sid Cleveland, Herb Engman, Francille Firebaugh, Gary Fitch, Bill Friedland, John Lincoln, Cindy Noble, Chris Pawelski, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Robert Gottlieb, Cathy Cohn Hertzel, Bruce John, Stuart Mitchell, Donald Naeye, Maureen Torrey, Jerry Verbridge, Earl Welker, Charles Wille, Rick Zimmerman, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - David Dik, Dale Corson, Cliff DeMay, Alison DeMarree, Keith Kennedy, Jeff Liddle, Tom Maloney, Dick McGuire, Laura Pedersen, Alice Sprout, Jerome Ziegler, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - George Amey, Joaquin Bermudez, Marsha Boyd, David Call, Nancy Croce, Kay Embrey, Steve Johnson, Bill McKee, Jim Schmidt, Velma Smith, Karen Tobin Hanson, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Series III. Programs
  - Development of Infant and Toddler Guidelines, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Guidelines for Day Care Programs for Migrant Infants and Toddlers - Birckmayer and Willis, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Migrant Nutrition Project, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Adolescent Task Orientation Involvement Project, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Program Funding, Inc. Combined Projects, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Right to Read (New York State Migrant Education), 1973 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Migrant Dental Education (with Project REACH and Lakes Area), 1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Comprehensive Health Education, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Oral Health Education Program, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Reading Is Fun-damental (RIF), 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Uninvolved Youth Project, 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Migrant Nutrition, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Learn and Earn (Program Funding, Inc.), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Comprehensive Health Program for Migrant Children, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Migrant Dental Education (1), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Migrant Dental Education (2), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Community Health Project (Wayne County), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Migrant Nutrition (1), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Migrant Nutrition (2), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Learn and Earn (with Program Funding, Inc.), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Health Education, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - USDA Food Service Program, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Campaign for Human Development (Catholic Church), 1976 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Sodus Central School and Town of Sodus, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Combined Migrant Education Projects, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Migrant Student Record Transfer System (MSRTS), 1976 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Lakes Area Regional Medical, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - North Rose-Wolcott (New York) Summer School, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Comprehensive Health (with Rushville Clinic), 1976 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Opening the Outdoors Proposals and Evaluation, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Opening the Outdoors, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Opening the Outdoors Reports, 1974-1977 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Opening the Outdoors, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Opening the Outdoors - H. Engman, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Opening the Outdoors (New York State Dept. of Education), 1976 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Opening the Outdoors, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Opening the Outdoors - Photo Album (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Opening the Outdoors - Sheri Morrison, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Western New York Migrant Day Care Centers - Speech, Language, Hearing, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Food Service Program for Children, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Comprehensive Migrant Health Education Project, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Wayne County Migrant Youth Project (Sodus and N. Rose-Wolcott Schools), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - MSRTS, Opening the Outdoors, Comprehensive Health, Nutrition, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Combined Migrant Nutrition Education, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Summer Enrichment Program - RESDP, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Migrant Handicapped Education Assessment Project, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Summer Enrichment Program, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Migrant Medical Services Education (1), 1979 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Migrant Medical Services Education (2), 1979 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Migrant Health and Nutrition Information (1), 1979 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Migrant Health and Nutrition Information (2), 1979 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Migrant Census, Parent Education and Analysis, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Goals for Youth, 1979-1983 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Goals for Youth - Program Guide (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Migrant Health and Nutrition Education, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Migrant Medical Services Education, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Rushville Health Center Report, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Migrant Parent Tutorial Project - Review - Laurie Kotloff, 1980-1982 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Migrant Family Communication Project - Roy Colle, Sue Travis, 1980-1982 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Migrant Medical Services Education, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Migrant Census, Parenting and Community Service, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Migrant Health and Nutrition Education, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Migrant Census, Parenting and Community Service, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Migrant Medical Services Education, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Migrant Health and Nutrition Education, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Migrant Health and Nutrition, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Migrant Census, MSRTS, Parent and Communications, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Literacy for Migrant Farmworkers - New York State Department of Education, 1983-1984 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Mina Shaughnessy Scholars Program - Kathy Fox (Castania), 1982 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Literacy Grant Application (not funded) - Mott, Davenport-Hatch, Gannett, Mina Shaughnessy Scholars, 1982-1983 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Literacy for Migrant Farmworkers, 1982-1985 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Agricultural Careers Subcontract with Rural Opportunities, Inc. - Proposal, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Agricultural Careers Subcontract with Rural Opportunities, Inc., 1983 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Agricultural Careers Development Project (with RNYFO) - Kay Embrey, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Literacy for Migrant Farmworkers - Mott Foundation, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Davenport-Hatch Foundation and Gannett proposal (Literacy), 1983 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Agricultural Careers Subcontract with Rural Opportunities, Inc., 1984 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Cornell Migrant Teen Pregnancy Project (New York State Education) - Florence Cherry - Not funded, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Migrant Family Health Voucher System (Proposal, denied), 1984 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - The Changing Migrant Scene Conference, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - ACTION, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Migrant Census MSRTS, Parent and Communications, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Migrant Medical Service Education, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - New York State Migrant Education Grant, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Literacy For Migrant Farmworkers (New York State Education Dept.) - Kathy Fox Castania, 1984-1988 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Student Service Learning Project with Migrant Farmworkers (ACTION), 1984-1988 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Agricultural Careers, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Using Community Volunteers with Migrant Farmworkers - ACTION, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 12)